here at the NFL scouting combine in
Indianapolis with defensive coordinator
Calvin Shepard. Entering your second
year, what is the biggest thing you
think you you learned or you developed
over the course of of your first season
as a defensive coordinator call plays?
>> Yeah, I would say the biggest probably
the most important thing um is finding
my rhythm on game day. Um leaning
learning the flow because there's so
many things that go on that people
probably don't know. Tim, as you know,
the communication, not just coach to
player, but coach to coach. Um, and
leaning on your staff, understanding
it's not you by yourself. It's not you
versus that team. It's not you and the
players. It's you, your coaches. You
know, you putting all this work and
listen to those guys, lean on them on
game day. Uh, and I think when you do
that, I've found and learned that these
guys get so ingratiated into it, you
know, and they feel like they're calling
it right there with you. Um, and I think
that's what we've built. Uh, I think
that's what these guys feel and you
know, I'm very fortunate to have all
these guys back with me.
>> You know, I'm glad you mentioned the
staff because there is a lot of
continuity w with that defensive staff
coming back. Just how important is that
for you going into your second season? I
know you talked about a little bit just
with some of the changes you've made in
the off season with with how you're
doing the cutups and stuff like that,
but just to have that continuity with
your staff, chef, going into your second
season. How important is that? How key
is that to to to that progression on
defense? Oh, it means everything to me
to be honest, Tim, because I don't have
to start over. You know, it's kind of
been years of all right, we lost this
coach, so we got to start over. You
know, we're going to change
schematically here. Let's start over.
And when you do that, you're not able,
in my opinion, to go to that next level.
Uh when you talk about 500 levels in
learning, you know, 100 level, 200,
three. Well, I feel like now we're able
to start off, especially with some of
our core guys that we've gone back, not
just coaches, but players at the 200,
300 level. We're not telling guys where
to line up and what your responsibility
is. We're now telling them how you can
execute that better. Situational
awareness, things like that. And you
know, Tim, you probably know I had a few
staffers with opportunities, man. It
kind of nerved me up a bit because it's
like
>> I feel like we really have something
special here. Uh, you know, as a as
overall organization, but as a defensive
staff, the chemistry we have, it's no
egos. All egos are left outside that
door. And when we meet, I think
everybody feels like they have a hand in
it. Um, and to be able to come in in
year two, guys already having ideas
because they were just in it. Yeah. And
ways to improve and not just me saying
this, this, this, I tell them this is
our scheme. So to be able to do this
together going into year two, I'm very
fortunate.
>> Guys had opportunities, but you also had
an opportunity to interview for a head
coaching job with Miami. Just talk me
through that process. What did you
learn? How does that how does going
through that maybe make you a little bit
better?
>> Yep. Just first and foremost, I want to
thank the entire Dolphins organization.
Steven Ross, Tom Garfinkle, Brandon
Shore, Dan Marino, uh Sully, of course,
man, those are phenomenal people. Uh
they definitely have the right people in
place to get that thing going. Um and I
learned a lot. I learned that my
philosophy and making sure you take
pressure off the head coaches, right? Uh
and now that's heightened even more.
>> You know, everybody say they want to sit
in these seats till you actually get the
chance to or about to and you feel that
weight. Um, you know, I mean, you got to
wear a hundred hats and it's what you
sign up for. You're the CEO of
corporation essentially when you take on
that role. Uh, from I just told people
just I mean before you even get to the
football and studying for the opponent,
it's so much that goes into it with
roster management,
um, staffing, support staff, making sure
you're doing things right as far as
practice, uh, and all this being on you.
Um, and if it doesn't go right, it's on
you. And if it goes well, you did and
like you just that ownership, you know,
that you have over that. Um, so just
making sure now I've taken all that
stuff in. And I just want to credit also
people within our organization. Uh, this
is stuff people don't know about, but
the Rob Lman's of the world, Jesse,
Anton,
um, Dan, uh, former coaches to be
honest, Ben, AG, these are all guys that
reached out to me when they knew I got
this opportunity. uh just you know
anything I could do and I leaned on them
all um and they all helped me in a way
to prepare.
>> Reminds you that it's a brotherhood in
isn't it?
>> Absolutely.
>> You've been busy you and your staff and
Dan with with the cutups the last you
know three weeks. Dan talked about it
here at the combine just how intense
it's been. I'm curious from your
perspective one area from the cutups
that that you liked you know and one
area that you're like okay this is
something that we need to focus on we
need to get better at. So, the one
positive from the cutups, maybe the the
thing that kept showing up that, okay, I
I like this about this defense. Let's
keep doing this. And then the flip side
of that, what do you need to improve on?
>> Yep. I think uh something that we were
able to do is the adjustability within
the scheme. It's something we hadn't
done before.
>> Uh and it really helped us this year. Um
>> it almost was like the players, you
heard them say like almost like they
know the plays, but it wasn't we
necessarily knew the exact play that was
coming. um some Connor Stallion stuff,
but it was the fact it was formationally
putting guys in optimal position per
coverage. Uh whether that be it uh 2x2,
3x1 slot empty. Um I don't think these
guys started to get a hold of why we
were actually checking the certain
things and say, "Oh, if we can push the
coverage here, I can cheat here. I can
do things." So that's what you're
talking about continuity now just being
able to start off. So, I think the same
look, presenting the same look to a
offense and then postnap changing. Um,
so they're seeing the same thing, same
thing and postnap. The young
quarterbacks really struggle with that.
Uh, that's something I thought we did
really well. Um, and being the dictator
on the field as far as that's what the
offense want to do. They want to have
the pin last with the motions, the
shifts, and and being able to grab the
pen back and saying, "I have an answer
for